Hello and welcome to Biodose Tools User Guide
This video explains how to estimate a dose
using the frequency of dicentrics
Do not consider second division cells
Each dicentric should be accompanied
by an acentric fragment
acentric fragments not related to a dicentric
should be considered as an extra fragment
A .txt file can be created to enter the data
Data can also be introduced manually, or from an Excel file
To estimate the dose, open RStudio to run Biodose Tools
To run Biodose Tools, type biodosetools::run_app()
on the R console and press Enter
Once Biodose Tools has loaded
click on "Dicentrics" on the sidebar and choose "Dose estimation"
Then, click on "Browse" to load a fitted curve from a RDS file
Select the .rds file you want to load
and click on "Preview data"
Now, click on "Load data from a file"
Select the .txt file you want to load
You can describe the circumstances of the accident in "Case description"
Click on "Calculate parameters" to calculate
N, X, mean, SE, DI, and the u-value
In "Dose estimation options" consider the circumstances of the accident
In this case it was an acute exposure,
and the u-value does not indicate overdispersion
Lastly, select the method to calculate the error
(the recommended option is Merkle's 83%-83%)
Click on "Estimate dose" to estimate the dose
Dose estimation results can be seen if you scroll down
You can interpret the obtained results in "Comments"
A report of the case can be downloaded